# Ronald Randolph

## Visual Artist

Address Venice, CA, 90291

WWW laronemcee.com

Phone (702) 324-8939

E-mail junkfoodrebellion@gmail.com

Creative multi-disciplined artist with 20 plus years of experience creating valuable network ties with art curators and art gallery owners. Highly passionate about art, technology and the creative processes involved. Fearless Artist willing to take creative risks and push conceptual boundaries. Adobe Photoshop and procreate proficiency.

## Skills

Visual storytelling	Excellent
Drawing and sketching	Excellent
Graphic arts	Excellent
Project Management	Excellent
Exhibit preparation	Excellent
Self-motivated professional	●●●● Excellent
Skilled in photoshop illustrator and procreate	●●●● Excellent

# Work History

2012-01 - Current

#### Fine Art Painter

Self-employed, Las Vegas, NV

- Gave educational art instruction to clients and students.
- Met with customers and clients to determine project needs and prepared proposals incorporating production schedules, scopes of work and budgets.
- Managed all art and office supply needs for art department.

2012-01 - Current

#### Freelance Illustrator

Self Employed, Las Vegas, NV

• Collaborated with marketing and art departments to create high-quality images and

illustrations to enhance publications and presentations.

- Applied color theory and lighting techniques in drawings and illustrations to add excitement, focus and depth.
- Added illustrations to company marketing collateral and promotional materials that reflected unified company brand.
- Used photoshop, illustrator and procreate to design program to create images for use in diverse clients' marketing campaigns.
- Produced computer-generated artwork to add depth and cohesiveness to technical journal and publication articles.
- Created and sold over 200 original paintings in 5 years

#### 2017-08 - 2019-01

# Art Gallery Dir

Emcee Studio And Gallery , Las Vegas, NV

- Contributed to creative process through original ideas and inspiration.
- Promoted events and exhibits via social media, email and other communication methods
- Developed and maintained relationships with artists and clientele, traveled to meet with clients and artists
- Moved and handled various types of artwork with exceptional care
- Networked at creative events to identify new talent and artistic works in local areas.
- Offered friendly and efficient service to all customers, handled challenging situations with ease.
- Procured talented individuals, performing artists and musicians to entertain guests during special events.

# Education

2010-08 - 2012-01 Some College (No Degree): Fine Arts

Indiana University Northwest - Gary, IN

2009-01 - 2010-01 Some College (No Degree): Graphic Design/animation

Purdue University Calumet - Hammond, IN

1997-09 - 1998-01 Some College (No Degree): Fine Arts

Vincennes University - Vincennes, IN

# Accomplishments

Sold and exhibited Art in 20 + group exhibits

sold and exhibited art in 5 solo exhibits curated 10 exhibits with over 50 artists

designed cover art and merch for recording artists displayed art in Las Vegas City Hall and the Nevada state museum

Donated artwork for The James Dewitt Yancey Foundation community fundraising event.

Donated artwork for a The Shade Tree community fundraising event. Had artwork shown on BET and local commercials and promo videos in Las Vegas owned and curated a gallery for 2 years